Elena Sacristán Sacristán

London - United Kingdom

Mobile: 07710263790 | Email: elena_sacristan@yahoo.es
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/elena-sacristan-sacristan
Online Resume: https://elenasacristan.github.io/MyResume/

Full Stack Web Developer seeking entry-level programming position.

After 10 years working within technical roles in the Market Research industry I have now decided to follow my passion and start a new career as a Web Developer.

CORE COMPETENCIES

CSS MongoDB	Diango	Γ	I	
	Djaligo	Font Awesome	Fireworks	Git
JavaScript Postgres Python	Bootstrap	Materialize		Heroku Slack

EDUCATION

November 2018-November 2019

Diploma: Software Development (European qualification level 5), Code Institute.

Accredited by the Edinburgh Napier University.

Grade: First Class Honours

September 2001 - June 2006

Degree: Bachelor of Electronic Engineering, Universidad de Alcalá, Madrid

* September 2005 - June 2006 (Erasmus program)

B Eng Electronic Engineering Final Project - Letterkenny Institute of Technology, Letterkenny (Ireland)

PROJECTS

TreeBooks – Fourth milestone project - https://github.com/elenasacristan/treebooks

- e-commerce website for a fictitious charity ('TreeBooks') whose aim is to raise money by renting second-hand books
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Python, Django, Heroku and Stripe

Time2Eat! – Third milestone project - https://github.com/elenasacristan/CookBook

- Website to save and edit recipes online, see recipes from other users, vote recipes and see the ranking of the best cooks
- HTML, CSS, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, MongoDB, Python, Flask and Heroku

HolidaysYa! - Second milestone project - https://github.com/elenasacristan/HolidaysYa

- Website to help users decide where to go on holidays based on the weather or budget by showing them a dashboard with information about prices and weather
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, D3.js, DC.js, Crossfilter.js and queue.js

The Monkees website - First milestone project - https://github.com/elenasacristan/the-monkees-website

- Website for The Monkees band that will be used by current and prospective fans to learn more about the band, listen to songs, keep up to date with the latest news and buy tickets
- > HTML, CSS and Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2015 - Current

Senior Survey Scripter / Fusion Insight & Strategy, London

- Programming online market research surveys
- > Improving the graphic design for the surveys and making them more user friendly
- Creating templates which shortened the survey set up time
- Cleaning and analysing large data files
- Creating macros in Excel in order to automatise tasks, reducing in some cases the time to execute a task from several hours to only some minutes
- Researching and testing different surveys platforms. Learning/adapting to different programming survey languages and settings
- ➤ Meeting very tight deadlines in a fast-paced business environment.

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2009 - August 2015

Sampling/DP Executive (Data Processing Team) / Ronin Corporation, London

- Using SQL queries to analyse and update databases
- > Setting up and sending emails to the respondents in the databases
- > Constantly improving processes (i.e. automatising repetitive tasks using macros)

October 2008 - June 2009

I'm originally from Spain and in October 2008 I moved to London in order to improve my English and travel around the rest of the UK, which I supported by working in various roles in the hospitality sector.

April 2007 - October 2008

Team Leader / Alfonso Benitez S.A. (group FCC. S.A.) Madrid, Spain

Grade: DISTINCTION

- > Managing the street cleaning contract of two districts in Madrid and 6 recycling points
- > Dealing with the client (city council) by phone and sending daily reports
- ➤ Holding meetings with The Union Representatives Committee to deal with everything related to the workers and meetings with the H&S experts and the company director to improve other aspects of the organisation

September 2006 - April 2007

Technical Electronic Engineer / SICA S.A. Madrid, Spain

- Working on the design and installation of control and supervision systems for electrical substations
- My role was to communicate the PLC's with the SCADA's creating the SCADA interface and drawing the designs with AutoCAD
- Meeting very strict deadlines

CERTIFICATES

February 2017 Introduction to Java Script, London Academy of IT (London)

April 2014 Web Design with HTML and CSS, London Academy of IT (London)

April - June 2010 EDEXCEL BTEC LEVEL 1 AWARD in GRAPHIC DESIGN (QCF), Waes (London)

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I enjoy volunteering and travelling. In 2012 I went to Morocco to help orphaned children, and in 2013 I went to Kenya to help the Masai community (www.originalvolunteers.com).

In my spare time I like to play beach and indoor volleyball and at present I am competing in the London League.